in early January of 2025
2025年1月初
a satellite captured a curious image of
一颗卫星捕捉到了一张奇怪的图像
something happening in the Chinese megacity of
中国特大城市发生了一些事情
Guangzhou near the country's southern coast
靠近中国南部海岸的广州
a drydock in the city was busy
城里的一个干船坞很忙
constructing this strange looking ship
建造这艘看起来很奇怪的船
something that a handful of foreign
一些外国的东西
intelligence analysts at the time
当时的情报分析师
suggested could be a Chinese landing vessel
可能是一艘中国登陆舰
and then only a couple of
然后只有几个
months later in March of 2025
三个月后的2025年3月
the completed vessel and two other similar
完成的船和另外两艘类似的船
looking ships responded by satellites again
寻找船只再次得到卫星的回应
this time off of China's far southern coastline
这次是在中国遥远的南部海岸线
practicing a series of interesting maneuvers
练习一系列有趣的动作
this time the satellite captured the three barges
这次卫星捕捉到了三艘驳船
connecting together to form a huge causeway from the
连接在一起形成一个巨大的堤道
rear most barge and then through the front barge
后驳船，然后通过前驳船
directly towards the beach with the accompanying
和随行人员一起直奔海滩
Chinese civilian cargo ships and ferries practicing
中国民用货船渡轮演练
right alongside them
就在他们旁边
and then only a few weeks later after that
然后仅仅几周后
a series of photos taken by the Chinese themselves of
中国人自己拍摄的一系列照片
the exercises began spreading around on the internet
演习开始在互联网上传播
showing the three barges from the perspective of
从的角度展示三艘驳船
being down on the ground on the beach itself
躺在沙滩上
showing the long causeway from the rear barge
显示从后驳船开始的长堤道
connecting all the way to the front barge with an
一直连接到前面的驳船
offloading ramp extending directly onto the beach
直接延伸到海滩的卸货坡道
interestingly just wide enough to accommodate
有趣的是，足够宽，可以容纳
the offloading of a heavy main battle tank
重型主战坦克的卸载
it didn't take very long for many analysts to
没过多久，许多分析师就
begin recognizing that these new barges could be
开始认识到这些新驳船可能是
a part of China's ever evolving strategy
中国不断发展的战略的一部分
to launch an all out invasion of
发动全面入侵
Taiwan at some point in the future
台湾在未来的某个时候
the island that the government
这个岛政府
of China regards as a rogue
中国认为是流氓
renegade province that China's leader Xi Jinping
中国领导人习近平的叛徒省份
has repeatedly promised will be brought under
一再承诺将被接管
Chinese Communist Party rule some way or another
中国共产党以某种方式统治
either through diplomacy or through force
要么通过外交手段要么通过武力
of course
当然
one of the biggest obstacles that has been standing in
一直以来最大的障碍之一
the way of an all out Chinese invasion of Taiwan for
中国全面入侵台湾的方式
decades has been the fact that Taiwan is an island
几十年来台湾是一个岛屿
in order to get their army over to that island
为了把他们的军队带到那个岛上
China will need to transport their soldiers
中国需要运送他们的士兵
vehicles and equipment over the sea
海上交通工具和设备
in a Titanic amphibious invasion
在泰坦尼克号的两栖入侵中
like a modern 21st century version of the d day
就像现代21世纪版本的d day
invasion of Normandy during World War II
二战期间入侵诺曼底
and China is aware that any amphibious invasion
中国知道任何两栖入侵
of an enemy consists of two different steps
敌人由两个不同的步骤组成
the first step is rather straightforward
第一步相当简单
and consists of actually assaulting the beach
包括袭击海滩
storming and overcoming local enemy positions
攻克当地敌人阵地
and establishing a localized beachhead
并建立本地化滩头阵地
the second step is more complicated
第二步更复杂
and is likely what these new barges
很可能这些新驳船
are designed to help out with
旨在帮助解决
after the initial beachhead is established
初始滩头阵地建立后
the invading force has to make the beachhead
侵略军必须占领滩头阵地
sustainable in order to actually hold on to it
可持续发展才能真正坚持下去
and to expand their control even
甚至扩大他们的控制
deeper into the enemy's territory
深入敌方领土
the beachhead has to be logistically supplied
滩头阵地需要后勤补给
with adequate amounts of reinforcements  ammunition
有足够数量的增援弹药
fuel  food
燃料食品
medical supplies and other materials to make sure
医疗用品和其他材料，以确保
that they don't just run out of supplies surrounded by
他们不只是耗尽了周围的补给
hostile territory and implode in on themselves
在敌对领土上自爆
so in order to make a beachhead sustainable
所以为了让滩头阵地可持续发展
the invading force usually has to take
入侵部队通常必须
over a nearby port that's ideally closely
在附近的港口附近
located to the initial beachhead
位于最初的滩头
through which they can then begin bringing in all of
通过它，他们可以开始引入所有
their necessary supplies and reinforcements for the
他们必要的补给和增援
troops to hold the beachhead and then expand beyond it
军队守住滩头阵地，然后向外扩张
but in most cases securing a nearby enemy
但大多数情况下都是为了保护附近的敌人
harbor to the beachhead that's still
港口到滩头
perfectly intact is no easy feat
完好无损绝非易事
during the Allied amphibious invasion
在盟军两栖入侵期间
of Normandy during World War II
二战期间的诺曼底
the allies solution to this problem were
盟国解决这个问题的方法是
the now famous Mulberry Harbours
现在著名的桑树港
which have no doubt been studied extensively
毫无疑问已经被广泛研究过了
by Chinese military planners for a possible
中国军事策划者可能会
Taiwan amphibious invasion today
今日台湾两栖入侵
rather than spending huge amounts of time and resources
而不是花费大量的时间和资源
trying to capture well defended enemy occupied ports
试图占领防守严密的敌军占领的港口
that would probably be sabotaged and damaged anyway and
反正可能会被破坏和损坏
take even more time to repair and bring back online
需要更多时间来修复和重新上线
the allies solution was to simply bring
盟国的解决方案是简单地
their own temporary portable harbors to
他们自己的临时便携式港口
the coast of Normandy instead
取而代之的是诺曼底海岸
merely hours after the allies had
就在盟军
established their beachheads in Normandy
在诺曼底建立了滩头阵地
after the initial d day amphibious assaults
在最初的d日两栖攻击之后
the many sections of the Mulberry Harbors were
桑树港的许多部分
towed from England across the channel and put into
从英国拖过海峡并投入
position in two different beachhead locations
在两个不同滩头阵地的位置
Mulberry a and Mulberry B
桑树A和桑树B
the Mulberry Harbours basically consisted
桑树港基本上包括
of a series of floating breakwaters  pontoons
一系列浮动防波堤浮筒
piers and floating roadways that the allies were then
当时盟军的码头和水上道路
able to stitch together and use to rapidly offload
能够缝合在一起并用于快速卸载
reinforcements and supplies through onto the beachheads
增援和补给进入滩头阵地
which enabled them to become sustainable and be able to
这使它们能够变得可持续并能够
expand deeper into the interior without the need to
无需深入内部
spend crucial time and effort capturing any of the
花费关键的时间和精力捕捉任何
sabotaged German occupied ports in northern France
破坏德国占领的法国北部港口
instead
相反
nonetheless  even during this operation
尽管如此，即使在这次行动中
Mulberry Harbor a was destroyed by a violent storm
桑树港被一场猛烈的风暴摧毁了
just a few days after it had been established
就在它成立几天后
limiting the allies to the use of only
将盟国限制在仅使用
Mulberry Harbor B for the next several months
未来几个月的Mulberry Harbor B
now for China's modern considerations for a
现在为中国的现代考虑一个
21st century amphibious invasion of Taiwan
21世纪两栖入侵台湾
there are many geographic facts about this part of
关于这部分有许多地理事实
the world that will make it even harder to pull off
这个世界将使它更难实现
than the Allied invasion of Normandy was
比盟军入侵诺曼底还要多
the distance that the Chinese invasion fleet will have
中国入侵舰队的距离
to travel across the Taiwan Strait will be roughly
穿越台湾海峡将大致
similar to the distance that the Allied invasion fleet
与盟军入侵舰队的距离相似
had to travel across the English Channel
不得不穿越英吉利海峡
and just like the allies
就像盟军一样
experienced at Normandy in 1944
1944年在诺曼底经历过
the Chinese can also expect
中国人也可以期待
that Taiwan's defenders today
今天台湾的守军
would likely sabotage their own ports rather than
可能会破坏自己的港口
risk them falling into Chinese hands intact
冒着他们完好无损地落入中国人手中的风险
which means that the Chinese will have to
这意味着中国人将不得不
bring their own ports with them in order to
带上他们自己的港口，以便
sustain their initial beachheads
维持他们最初的滩头阵地
however
然而
a significant amount of the Taiwanese coast is ringed
台湾海岸的很大一部分被环抱
by extensive coral reefs that in some locations can
由广泛的珊瑚礁，在某些地方可以
stretch for hundreds of meters off the beaches
在海滩上绵延数百米
severely complicating the ability for an
使能力严重复杂化
invasion force to bring their own Mulberry
入侵部队自带桑树
Harbor style portable ports to bear
港口式便携式端口承载
moreover
此外
the island of Taiwan just also has very few suitable
台湾岛也只有很少合适的
beaches that a traditional amphibious invasion force
传统的两栖入侵部队
can choose from to attack with any good odds of success
可以选择任何成功的可能性
the island only has a total of 14 so called red
岛上总共只有14个所谓的红色
beaches dotted around the island where conditions are
岛上星罗棋布的海滩
considered optimal for an amphibious assault
被认为是两栖攻击的最佳选择
where the coral reefs extending from the
那里的珊瑚礁从
shoreline are either small or non existent
海岸线要么很小，要么不存在
where the terrain is relatively flat and
那里的地形相对平坦
easier to assault than the rugged
比崎岖更容易攻击
towering cliffs that are seen across
高耸的悬崖
most of the island's east coast
该岛东海岸的大部分地区
and where the beaches themselves are also located
以及海滩本身的位置
nearby to strategically crucial targets for the Chinese
靠近中国的重要战略目标
to capture such as Taiwan's capital and the largest
以捕获如台湾的首都和最大的
city in the north Taipei and Taiwan's principal and
台北北部的城市和台湾的主要和
largest maritime port down in the south Kaohsiung
南高雄最大的海港
however  the vulnerability of all 14 of these red
然而，所有14个红色的漏洞
beaches are very well understood by Taiwan
海滩是非常了解台湾
and so they're consequently the most heavily fortified
因此，它们是戒备最森严的
and well defended beaches on the entire island
以及整个岛上防守严密的海滩
making any traditional amphibious
制造任何传统的两栖
assaults on them a difficult task
袭击他们是一项艰巨的任务
all of these problems though can potentially be
所有这些问题都可能是
solved by China's new invasion barges that have
由中国新的入侵驳船解决
been spreading around the internet these past few
过去几年一直在互联网上传播
months which western intelligence sources have
西方情报来源已经
nicknamed the shuiqiao class of vessels literally
外号水桥级船
Mandarin Chinese for water bridge
水桥的普通话
when hypothetically approaching the Taiwanese coast
当假设接近台湾海岸时
these suikow barges
这些suikow驳船
which will probably always operate in pairs of three
它可能总是三对运行
will carefully position themselves
会仔细定位自己
one after the other in a row
一个接一个地连续
with the smaller barge of the trio in the front
三人组中较小的驳船在前面
the medium sized barge in the center
中间的中型驳船
and the largest sized barge back in the rear
最大的驳船在后面
each of the barges carries a set of super
每艘驳船都载有一套超级
heavy retractable legs with them on board
船上有沉重的可伸缩腿
while the barges are still in transport these legs
当驳船还在运输这些腿的时候
will be retracted and stowed above the ship
将被收回并存放在船的上方
but once they're in position near the beachhead
但是一旦他们在滩头阵地附近就位
the legs will be lowered to pin them
腿会被放下来固定它们
down to the sea bed beneath them and to
直到它们下面的海底
lift their hulls out of the water
把它们的船体抬出水面
giving them increased stability in the choppy coastal
让他们在波涛汹涌的海岸更加稳定
waters almost like miniature offshore oil platforms
水域几乎就像微型海上石油平台
each of the barges also has a tower in
每艘驳船也有一座塔
their front and a long bridge stored on
他们的正面和一座长桥存放在
their decks while in transport
他们在运输途中的甲板
once the legs have stabilized the barges in place
一旦船腿固定住驳船
the towers at the front will telescope out
前面的塔楼会向外望去
their bridges to create a giant portable
他们的桥梁创造了一个巨大的便携式
causeway extending out from the rear barge to
堤道从后驳船延伸到
the center barge to the front barge to the shore
中间驳船到前面驳船到岸边
extending out nearly 825 meters from the rear barge
从后驳船延伸出近825米
it's also been suggested by several other analysts
其他几位分析家也提出了这一建议
that these heavy duty bridges will be capable of
这些重型桥梁将能够
supporting and fitting heavy vehicles such as armored
支撑和安装装甲等重型车辆
personnel carriers and even main battle tanks
运兵车甚至主战坦克
together
一起
the Shui Kai barges effectively function as both a
水开驳船有效地发挥了
movable port and a movable bridge at the same time
活动端口和活动桥同时
working in unison with Chinese civilian roll on roll
与中国平民齐心协力
off or ro ro ferries commandeered for military service
征用渡轮服兵役
The People's Liberation Army can then rapidly
人民解放军可以迅速
dock these ro ro ferries carrying vehicles
停靠这些运载车辆的滚装渡轮
with the larger rear barge and disgorge their
用更大的后驳船并吐出他们的
heavy vehicles and equipment into it
重型车辆和设备进入其中
they can then rapidly storm ahead across the
然后他们就可以迅速横跨
causeway and directly onto the beachhead
堤道直接开到滩头
two analysts affiliated with the China Maritime Studies
中国海事研究所的两位分析员
Institute J Michael Dorn and Thomas Schugart argued in
迈克尔·多恩研究所和托马斯·舒加特在
a paper they wrote in March 2025 about these Xuejiao
他们在2025年3月写的一篇关于这些雪椒的论文
barges that they would likely be capable of offloading
他们可能能够卸载的驳船
onto the beach an entire heavy combined arms battalion
整个重型联合兵力营都在海滩上
including roughly 150 vehicles in only about 40 to 60
包括大约150辆汽车，只有大约40到60辆。
minutes after they had extended their causeway
在他们延长堤道的十分钟后
over the course of a full day
在一整天的过程中
they could theoretically unload
理论上他们可以卸货
several hundred armored vehicles
几百辆装甲车
all brought to them by any number of China's
都是中国人给他们带来的
dozens of civilian ro ro ferries commandeered for
几十艘民用轮渡被征用
military service which have all been intentionally
服兵役都是故意的
designed for dual use purposes in mind with the
专为双重用途而设计
capability to handle onloading and offloading
处理装卸的能力
heavy duty military vehicles like tanks
坦克等重型军用车辆
with their long length far out from the beach
它们的长度远离海滩
the ro ro ferries will be able to safely offload
滚装渡轮将能够安全卸货
all of their vehicles onto the rear schwe cow
他们所有的车都在后面的母牛上
barge without any fear of them running aground in
不用担心他们会搁浅
the shallower waters closer to the beach
靠近海滩的浅水区
with their very shallow draft and
他们的吃水很浅
distance out from the shoreline
远离海岸线
the Xueqiao barges also appear to be
雪桥驳船似乎也是
designed to overcome Taiwan's coastal
旨在克服台湾沿海
coral reefs that ring most of the island
珊瑚礁环绕着岛的大部分
opening up more potential beaches beyond the 14 well
在14井之外开辟更多潜在海滩
known and well defended Red Beaches that the
著名和防御良好的红色海滩
Chinese invasion force could potentially assault
中国入侵部队可能会发动袭击
going even further
更进一步
the Shui kaol barges could also
水科尔驳船也可以
theoretically extend their causeway to
理论上把他们的堤道延伸到
connect directly to one of Taiwan's coastal highways
直接连接到台湾的沿海公路
disgorging their vehicles directly to the island's
直接把车开到岛上
highway system and ignoring the beaches altogether
高速公路系统完全无视海滩
this is potentially the biggest threat that the
这可能是最大的威胁
new Xueqiao barges pose to Taiwan's defense
新的雪桥驳船构成台湾的防御
they've been estimated by some analysts to
一些分析家估计他们
potentially expand the number of beaches that
有可能扩大海滩的数量
the PLA could land on Taiwan by around 40 on
解放军可以在40年前后登陆台湾
top of the original 14 red beaches
原始14个红色海滩之巅
greatly expanding the number of potential
大大扩大了潜力的数量
beaches that the Taiwanese will now have to
台湾人现在不得不去的海滩
consider preparing for their defense
考虑为他们的辩护做准备
and risking them spreading out their limited
冒着他们分散有限资源的风险
resources too thin and leaving behind weaker
资源太薄，留下的是更弱的
vulnerable defenses at some beaches that the PLA
解放军在一些海滩上脆弱的防御
could find and exploit during an invasion scenario
可以在入侵场景中找到并利用
the PLA would likely only utilize the Xueqiao
解放军可能只使用雪桥
barges after their navy and air force had already
在他们的海军和空军已经
achieved maritime and aerial supremacy
海空制霸
and after the initial beachheads on the shore
在海岸上的滩头后
have already been established by the first
已经由第一个建立
wave of d day style amphibious assaults
d日式两栖攻击浪潮
granting the PLA the ability to then rapidly offload
赋予PLA快速卸载的能力
their heavy equipment and supplies onto the island to
他们的重型设备和补给运到岛上
press on the assault deeper into the island's interior
继续深入岛屿内部
if the shuiyang class barges arrive too early without
如果水阳级驳船太早到达没有
PLA maritime or aerial supremacy established first
中国人民解放军首次确立海上或空中霸权
they'll just be sitting ducks while trying
他们只会坐以待毙
to offload their equipment and will be
卸下他们的设备，并将
easy targets to defending missiles
防御导弹的轻松目标
drones and artillery
无人机和大炮
moreover  the satellite images that have captured the
此外，卫星图像捕捉到了
Chui Kiao Barjis practicing have so far only
Chui Kiao Barjis练习到目前为止只有
shown them operating within calm waters
显示他们在平静的水域中行动
which might mean that they could struggle
这可能意味着他们可能会挣扎
in rougher weather conditions that commonly
在恶劣的天气条件下
happen within the Taiwan Strait
发生在台湾海峡内
just like with the Mulberry Harbors
就像桑树港一样
experienced during the Normandy landings
经历过诺曼底登陆
when one of them was destroyed by inclement
当其中一个被恶意摧毁时
weather within only a matter of days
几天内的天气
a second set of Shuihao barges have already been
第二批水豪驳船已经
observed by satellites to be under construction in
卫星观测到正在建造中
the same Guangzhou shipyard in China right now
现在中国的同一个广州造船厂
and if China ends up building enough of them
如果中国最终建造了足够多的核武器
it's conceivable that they could help China
他们有可能帮助中国
overcome one of their greatest challenges of all
克服他们最大的挑战之一
when it comes to an invasion of Taiwan
说到入侵台湾
seizing control of the island before anyone from the
在任何来自
outside world can intervene against them and stop them
外部世界可以干预并阻止他们
like the United States Japan and Australia
比如美国、日本和澳大利亚
if the initial PLA amphibious assaults are
如果PLA最初的两栖攻击是
successful at establishing their beachheads on
成功建立滩头阵地
Taiwan like the Normandy landings were
就像诺曼底登陆一样
and then if the Chinese can bring in their SWI Cal
然后如果中国人能带来他们的SWI Cal
barges and their commandeered civilian ro ro ferries
驳船及其征用的民用滚装渡轮
within hours of that happening like the allies were
几个小时内就像盟军一样
able to do with their Mulberry Harbours in Normandy
能够处理他们在诺曼底的桑树港
Thomas Schugart wrote in his paper that I
托马斯·舒加特在他的论文中写道
mentioned earlier that it would be conceivable
之前提到可以想象
that the PLA could unload up to eight heavy
PLA可以卸下多达八个重型
brigades complete with all of their vehicles  supplies
各旅装备齐全
and around 60,000 troops on Taiwan during just the
和大约六万军队在台湾
first wave of the attack within just the first 24 hours
最初24小时内的第一波袭击
with significant reinforcements being
有重要的增援
delivered over the following few days
在接下来的几天内交付
if the PLA could achieve a rapid
如果解放军能实现快速
takeover of Taiwan before the outside
先于外部接管台湾
world even had the time to react to it
世界甚至有时间对此做出反应
then would they
那他们会吗？
some other analysts argue that in this light
其他一些分析家认为，从这个角度来看
the Shui Kai bao barges are designed as a
水开宝驳船设计为
psychological weapon just as much as a real weapon
心理武器和真正的武器一样多
they serve as a major symbol that China is very
它们是中国非常重要的象征
serious about investing resources into
认真投入资源
establishing their ability to actually invade Taiwan
建立他们实际入侵台湾的能力
and they add a degree of plausibility to Xi
他们给习增添了一定程度的合理性
Jinping's frequent threats of invasion
习近平频繁的入侵威胁
China naturally would rather that Taiwan
中国自然宁愿台湾
surrender without a fight at all
不战而降
and convincing Taiwan's leadership that
并说服台湾领导层
the invasion will be both inevitable and
入侵将是不可避免的
successful is the best way to do that
成功是最好的方法
and these mu Shu cow barges certainly send a
这些木树牛驳船肯定会送一个
message that the odds of an invasion are at
入侵几率为
least more plausible than they were before  regardless
至少比以前更合理
in order to even use the barges in the first place
为了在第一时间使用驳船
the PLA will have to face fierce
解放军将不得不面对激烈的
resistance from determined Taiwanese
来自意志坚定的台湾人的抵抗
defenders while crossing the Taiwan Strait
穿越台湾海峡时的防御者
and while assaulting the beaches to
在袭击海滩的同时
establish the initial preliminary beachheads
建立初步的初步滩头阵地
and they could potentially face
他们可能会面临
determined American Japanese Filipino and
坚定的美国日本菲律宾和
Australian auxiliary defenses as well
还有澳大利亚的辅助防御系统
they could all work to deny them the
他们都可以努力否认他们
ability to even accomplish this first
甚至有能力先完成这件事
phase of the infamous assault altogether
臭名昭著的袭击阶段
and render the Shui Kaow barges a rather moot point
并使水桥驳船成为一个相当有争议的问题
so in order to reinforce both the psychological
所以为了加强心理
and real potential of the Shui Ka barrages
和水卡弹幕的真正潜力
China has to be able to incredibly
中国必须能够难以置信地
threaten the destruction of any allied
威胁摧毁任何盟军
intervention on Taiwan's behalf as well
也代表台湾进行干预
in order to try and deter any Allied intervention
为了阻止盟军的介入
from happening in the first place that could slow
从一开始就发生，这可能会减缓
their invasion down and potentially defeat them
他们的入侵并有可能击败他们
and in order to understand how the PLA is doing that
为了了解解放军是如何做到这一点的
we actually have to travel very far away
我们其实要去很远的地方
from Taiwan and the seas around the
来自台湾和周围的海洋
island to a very unlikely location
去一个不太可能的地方
the remote and sparsely populated deserts of far
遥远而人烟稀少的沙漠
northern and Northwestern China thousands of kilometers
中国北部和西北数千公里
away
离开
this is the Dingjin Test and Training Base
这里是定金试训基地
located in China's section of the Gobi Desert
位于中国部分戈壁沙漠
a massive facility used by the People's Liberation
人民解放组织使用的大型设施
Army Air Force for weapons integration testing
陆军空军用于武器集成测试
training and tactics development
训练和战术发展
it is an ideal location for them to do all
这是他们做所有事情的理想地点
of this because it's in a very remote
因为它在一个非常偏远的地方
sparsely populated location with huge
人烟稀少的位置，巨大的
amounts of wide open airspace
开放空域的数量
leading some analysts to compare the importance of
导致一些分析师比较
Ding Xing to China to Nellis Air Force Base in the
丁星到中国的内利斯空军基地
deserts of Nevada to the United States
从内华达沙漠到美国
and relatively nearby to the Dingxin Test and
而且离定心试验比较近
Training Base out in another one of China's
在中国的另一个训练基地
remote deserts known as the Taklamakan
被称为塔克拉玛干的偏远沙漠
satellite imagery has recently captured a lot of
卫星图像最近捕捉到了大量
things that kind of seem to indicate what the People's
似乎表明人民的
Liberation Army Air Force is actively training for
解放军空军正在积极训练
from the first to January of 2024
从2024年1月1日到1月
Planet Labs released an image that one of their
行星实验室发布了一张图片
satellites had captured in China's remote Taklamakan
卫星在中国偏远的塔克拉玛干捕获到
desert  showing what looks like a mock
沙漠显示出什么看起来像一个模拟
up of an aircraft carrier
航空母舰
and not just any aircraft carrier
而且不是一般的航空母舰
but a nearly perfect 1 to 1 identical mock
但是一个近乎完美的1比1相同的模拟
up of one of America's most advanced
是美国最先进的
current nuclear powered super carriers
目前的核动力超级航母
the Gerald R Ford class
Gerald R Ford级
there is a structure in the mock up that's almost
模型中有一个结构几乎
precisely in the same location as the Ford class's
与福特级的位置完全相同
island  and there are exactly four mock up catapult
岛，正好有四个模拟弹射器
launcher tracks on the deck that are located exactly
甲板上的发射器轨道准确定位
where they appear on the real Ford class carrier
它们出现在真正的福特级航母上
based on Planet Labs data
基于行星实验室的数据
it appears that the PLA began
看来解放军开始
constructing this mock up US carrier in
建造这艘模拟美国航母
the desert sometime in November of 2023
沙漠在2023年11月的某个时候
fairly recently
最近
however  going further back in time
然而回到更远的时间
there's been a general outline of an aircraft
有一个飞机的大致轮廓
carrier here in this exact location for a while
承运人在这个确切位置呆了一段时间
since at least 2021
至少从2021年开始
and before it was completely filled in with a
在它完全被一个
full aircraft carrier that we can see now
我们现在可以看到的完整的航空母舰
the PLA had built two smaller aircraft
解放军制造了两架较小的飞机
carriers within the overall silhouette
整体轮廓内的载体
and interestingly
有趣的是
this aircraft carrier is far from the only
这艘航空母舰远非唯一
American ship that the Chinese have built a 1
中国造的美国船
to 1 replica of out here in the desert
到沙漠里的一个复制品
in fact the area is almost littered with them
事实上，这个地区几乎到处都是它们。
Just four and a/2 kilometers away to the
只有4.5公里远
northwest is another full scale replica of
西北是另一个完整的复制品
another US Ford class aircraft carrier
另一艘美国福特级航空母舰
and dotted all around nearby are multiple 1
附近点缀着多个1
to 1 mock UPS of what appear to be Arleigh
到1个看起来像Arleigh的模拟UPS
Burke class guided missile destroyers
伯克级导弹驱逐舰
one of the US Navy's most modern and capable class of
美国海军最现代化和最有能力的一类
destroyers at the present that are typically used to
目前的驱逐舰通常用于
escort carriers in a strike group formation
以战斗群编队护送航母
but most interestingly of all is this line
但最有趣的是这条线
that snakes across the desert in between all
蜿蜒穿过沙漠
of these mock UPS of US warships
这些美国军舰的模拟UPS
this line appears to be a very large railroad
这条线似乎是一条非常大的铁路
roughly six meters in width
宽约6米
approaching four to five times as
接近四到五倍
wide as a usual railroad is
像通常的铁路一样宽
interestingly
有趣的是
this super wide railroad begins at what
这条超宽铁路始于什么地方
appears to be a storage facility of some sort
似乎是某种储存设施
and then extends for several kilometers in a straight
然后直线延伸数公里
line before curving rapidly through the desert and then
在快速穿过沙漠之前排成一排，然后
curving again to simply end in the middle of nowhere
再次弯曲，只是在一个偏僻的地方结束
the railroad doesn't curve to avoid
铁路不会弯曲以避免
any obstacles in the flat desert
平坦沙漠中的任何障碍
and the reason why it curves this way starts to
它这样弯曲的原因开始
become apparent when you see other photos of the
当你看到其他照片时变得明显
railroad and understand what its true purpose is
铁路并了解其真正目的是什么
yeah
是呀
the PLA is using the railroad to load up 1 to 1 models
PLA正在使用铁路装载1对1的模型
of US warships like the Ford class aircraft carrier
像福特级航空母舰这样的美国军舰
and then sends them down the railroad to
然后把他们送到铁路上
simulate a moving target for the Air
为空中模拟移动目标
Force and Rocket Force to fire at
火箭军和火箭军
that curve through the desert appears designed to
穿过沙漠的曲线似乎是为了
simulate a carrier's evasive maneuvers through the
模拟航母通过
ocean that it would take to avoid an incoming missile
躲避来袭导弹所需的海洋
there's other satellite photos of mock up
还有其他的卫星照片
carriers on this exact railroad blown to bits
这条铁路上的承运人被炸成碎片
after being targeted by missiles and rockets
被导弹和火箭瞄准后
and there are satellite photos of the stationary
还有卫星照片
aircraft targets blown to pieces as well
飞机目标也被炸成碎片
it's pretty clear what the PLA is preparing for here
很明显解放军在这里做什么准备
but if it wasn't any more clear
但如果不是更清楚的话
the location of all of these ship mock UPS
所有这些船舶模拟UPS的位置
in the Taklamakan desert isn't just for
在塔克拉玛干沙漠不仅仅是为了
the remoteness and clear open skies
遥远而晴朗的天空
the location is also about 26 kilometers away
地点也在26公里左右
from known People's Liberation Army Rocket
来自已知的解放军火箭
Force launch sites that are located in China's
强制位于中国的发射场
Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region
内蒙古自治区
which is just about the same distance to simulate
这与模拟距离大致相同
long range missile strikes from the interior of
远程导弹从内部打击
central China into the South China Sea
中国中部进入南海
a region that China claims almost in its entirety
中国几乎宣称对整个地区拥有主权
against the competing claims of the Philippines
反对菲律宾的主张
Vietnam and Malaysia
越南和马来西亚
far away in the similarly remote deserts of Inner
在遥远的内陆沙漠
Mongolia near to those PLA Rocket Force launch sites is
靠近解放军火箭军发射场的蒙古是
another curious creation that the PLA built here
解放军在这里建造的另一个奇怪的创造
around the end of the year in 2022 which might not look
大约在2022年底，这可能看起来不像
like very much at first until you see this other
一开始非常喜欢，直到你看到另一个
satellite image below it with the same roads
下面的卫星图像显示相同的道路
highlighted in red
用红色突出显示
this is an almost exact 1 to 1 mock up of the area
这几乎是该地区的1比1模型
around the Presidential Office in downtown Taipei
台北市中心总统府附近
the capital city of Taiwan
台湾的首都
that is similar to the National Mall in Washington DC
类似于华盛顿特区的国家广场
that's the site of most of Taiwan's most critical
那里是台湾最重要的
and sensitive government offices and buildings
和敏感的政府办公室和建筑
conveniently located nearby to a PLA Air Force
靠近PLA空军
aerial bombing and gunnery practice range
空中轰炸和射击练习靶场
this mock up is likely being used by the PLA
这个模型很可能被PLA使用
Air Force to simulate aerial strikes on the most
空军模拟空袭最多
sensitive part of the Taiwanese capital
台湾首都的敏感地区
China's testing of aerial attacks here and their
中国在这里测试空袭
testing of anti ship missiles at the site in the
反舰导弹的测试
Taklamakan desert on 1 to one mock UPS of US
塔克拉玛干沙漠在美国的1对1模拟UPS上
warships that sometimes even move and take
战舰有时甚至会移动
simulated evasive maneuvers is a clear indication
模拟躲避演习是一个明确的迹象
of China's evolving military capabilities
中国不断发展的军事能力
and their ability to target US warships
以及他们瞄准美国军舰的能力
and to attack the US's ability to project
并攻击美国的投射能力
power into the Western Pacific
进入西太平洋
and they're clearly not even
他们显然不公平
really trying to hide any of it
真的想隐瞒这一切
like the Xuejiao invasion barges
就像雪娇入侵驳船
the targeting of 1 to 1 mock UPS of US warships in
以美国军舰的1比1模拟UPS为目标
the Taklamakan desert sends a clear message from
塔克拉玛干沙漠发出了明确的信息
Beijing to Washington that America's warships will
北京向华盛顿表示，美国军舰将
be vulnerable and potentially sunk if they choose
易受攻击，如果他们愿意，可能会沉没
to intervene militarily on behalf of Taiwan the day
代表台湾进行军事干预
the invasion eventually comes
入侵终将到来
and so they serve both a
所以他们同时服务于
psychological as well as a real purpose
心理和真正的目的
over the past several years
在过去的几年里
China has embarked on the largest military
中国已经开始了最大的军事行动
build up ever witnessed in human history
建立在人类历史上前所未见的
and it's been a build up that has largely been
这是一个很大程度上
designed to counter US strengths in the Pacific theater
旨在对抗美国在太平洋战区的优势
China has poured resources into the People's
中国向人民投入了大量资源
Liberation Army Rocket Force to make it the
解放军火箭军
largest land based missile force in the world today
当今世界上最大的陆基导弹部队
giving them somewhere in the ballpark of thirty
让他们在30岁左右的地方
100 conventionally armed ballistic and cruise
100常规武装弹道和巡航
missiles of all different kinds of ranges to
各种射程的导弹
work with during a conflict over Taiwan
在台湾冲突中合作
these missiles give China the ability to launch
这些导弹使中国有能力发射
enormous salvos of attacks against military targets on
对军事目标的猛烈攻击
Taiwan itself before launching the main amphibious
台湾自己在发射主要两栖导弹之前
invasion
入侵
and they also give China the ability if they so
如果他们这样做，他们也给了中国能力
choose to attack US and allied military targets
选择攻击美国和盟国的军事目标
throughout the Western Pacific from the relative
从相对的西太平洋
safety of the Chinese mainland as well
中国大陆的安全也是如此
with hundreds of their longer range
拥有数百个更远的射程
conventional missiles capable of striking
能够打击的常规导弹
targets accurately as far away as Guam
目标精确到关岛
the fear on the American side is that China is equipped
美国方面担心中国有装备
with enough of these anti ship missiles to attack
有足够的反舰导弹攻击
virtually every US warship in the South China Sea and
几乎每艘在南中国海的美国军舰
nearby Taiwan with enough firepower to overwhelm each
附近的台湾有足够的火力压倒每一个
individual ship's own onboard missile defense systems
单独舰载导弹防御系统
the US of course is well aware of the Chinese
美国当然很清楚中国人
missile threat to their surface warships
导弹威胁到他们的水面战舰
which is a major part of why
这是原因的主要部分
the US military has shifted
美军已经转移了
so much to a strategy of
这么多的策略
countering China by positioning air
用空中定位对抗中国
missile and rapid amphibious response assets
导弹和快速两栖反应装备
of their own nearby to Taiwan on land bases in
在台湾附近的陆地基地
Japan and the Philippines instead
而是日本和菲律宾
but China has been hard at work
但中国一直在努力工作
developing other counters as well
也在开发其他计数器
China has a vastly vastly larger capacity
中国的产能要大得多
to construct new ships than the US or any
建造比美国或任何
other country on the world has
世界上其他国家有
the US currently only possesses
美国目前只拥有
four state owned shipyards
四个国有造船厂
while China possesses dozens of them
而中国拥有数十个
China possesses a whopping 230 times the
中国拥有高达230倍的
shipbuilding capacity of the United States right now
美国现在的造船能力
and to put it in a perspective for you
从你的角度来看
just one single state owned shipbuilder in China built
中国只有一家国有造船厂
more vessels by tonnage last year in 2024 alone
仅去年2024年就增加了船舶吨位
than the United States has collectively built
比美国集体建造的还要多
since the end of World War II to the present
从二战结束至今
a fact that has helped China seize the
这一事实帮助中国抓住了
title of the world's largest navy today
当今世界上最大海军的称号
and the types of ships that China is building are not
中国正在建造的船只类型不是
only designed to carry out an invasion of Taiwan
只是为了入侵台湾
like the Shui Kai barges and the countless dual
就像水开驳船和无数的双重
use civilian and military ro ro ferries
使用民用和军用滚装渡轮
but some of them are also designed
但其中一些也是设计的
specifically to counter some of the U s
专门针对美国的一些
Navy's few remaining strengths in this theater
海军在这个战区仅存的一点力量
while the PLA rocket force has been carefully
而PLA火箭部队一直小心翼翼
calibrated to counter U s surface warships
校准以对抗美国水面战舰
that still leaves behind the incredible
这仍然留下了令人难以置信的
the incredibly advanced and capable US nuclear
令人难以置信的先进和强大的美国核武器
submarine fleet that operates beneath the surface that
在水下作业的潜艇舰队
the Rocket Forces missiles will not be able to reach
火箭部队的导弹将无法到达
the US has by far the largest and the most
美国拥有迄今为止最大和最多的
competent nuclear submarine fleet in the world
世界上有能力的核潜艇舰队
that could be brought to bear on China's Taiwan
这可能会对中国台湾产生影响
invasion fleet as it crosses the Taiwan Strait
穿越台湾海峡的入侵舰队
but China is working on counters
但中国正在柜台上工作
to this advantage as well
也有这个优势
one of the ways that the geography of the
地理的方式之一
Taiwan Strait actually benefits China in this
台湾海峡在这方面实际上对中国有利
way is how relatively shallow it is
方式是它有多浅
the average depth throughout it
整个的平均深度
is only about 60 meters
只有大约60米
making it much easier to find and attack
让它更容易被发现和攻击
submarines operating there than in deeper waters
在那里作业的潜艇比在更深的水域
China's newest class of guided missile stealth frigate
中国最新的导弹隐形护卫舰
the Type 054B was just recently commissioned into the
054B型最近刚刚被委托进入
People's Liberation Army Navy in January of 2025
2025年1月解放军海军
and it is purpose built to be
它是专门建造的
an anti submarine warship
一艘反潜战舰
China has the huge shipbuilding capacity to begin
中国拥有庞大的造船能力
rapidly churning out a ton of these anti submarine
迅速制造出大量的反潜武器
stealth frigates over the coming years
未来几年的隐形护卫舰
and if they can concentrate enough of
如果他们能集中足够的精力
them in the Taiwan Strait to escort the
他们在台湾海峡护航
invasion fleet by the time it happens
入侵舰队在它发生的时候
they can pose a major threat to the
它们会对
operation of any US nuclear submarine
任何美国核潜艇的运行
operating beneath the Taiwan Strait
在台湾海峡下作业
while the rocket force on the Chinese mainland can pose
而中国大陆的火箭部队可以摆姿势
a similarly major threat to the operation of any U s
对任何美国行动的类似重大威胁
service warships operating nearby to Taiwan as well
在台湾附近也有服役军舰
greatly raising the stakes for the U s
大大提高了美国的赌注
to decide on intervening or not
决定是否干预
and China is attempting to use their massive military
中国正试图利用其庞大的军事力量
build up to make the potential costs of intervention
增加干预的潜在成本
clear for other US allies in the Pacific as well
美国在太平洋的其他盟友也可以
most notably Australia
最著名的是澳大利亚
earlier this year on February 11th of 2025 a Chinese
今年早些时候，2025年2月11日，一名中国人
People's Liberation Army Navy frigate appeared off the
中国人民解放军海军护卫舰出现在
northern coast of Australia and then sailed through the
然后航行穿过澳大利亚北部海岸
Torres Strait between Australia and Papua New Guinea
澳大利亚和巴布亚新几内亚之间的托雷斯海峡
this attracted only minor attention until
这只引起了轻微的关注，直到
later on while off of Australia's east coast
稍后在澳大利亚东海岸
the initial frigate was joined by two additional PLAN
最初的护卫舰由另外两艘PLAN加入
warships a cruiser and a replenishment tanker as they
战舰、巡洋舰和补给油轮
collectively transited through the Coral Sea and
集体穿越珊瑚海
continued moving further south before briefly entering
在短暂进入之前继续向南移动
into Australia's exclusive economic zone near Sydney
进入悉尼附近的澳大利亚专属经济区
but the attention the PLAN ships were receiving in
但是PLAN船只受到的关注
the Australian media reached an almost full on panic
澳大利亚媒体几乎陷入了恐慌
only a few days later when the vessels began
仅仅几天后，当船只开始时
issuing radio broadcasts to airlines warning them
向航空公司发出无线电广播警告他们
that they were conducting a series of live fire
他们正在进行一系列实弹射击
exercises in between Australia and New Zealand
澳大利亚和新西兰之间的演习
The Australian Civil Aviation Service was forced into
澳大利亚民航局被迫
issuing an emergency alert that caused almost 50
发出紧急警报，造成近50人死亡
planes to divert their course to avoid the area
飞机改变航线以避开该地区
from there the PLA and ships continued traveling south
从那里解放军和船只继续南下
of Tasmania entering into and out of Australia's
塔斯马尼亚岛进出澳大利亚的
exclusive economic zone again then traveled west to
专属经济区再次向西
within only 170 nautical miles of Perth just days after
距离珀斯仅170海里
a US nuclear submarine had visited a nearby base
一艘美国核潜艇访问了附近的基地
before then heading up north back towards China
然后向北返回中国
again after having nearly spent a month completely
又一次完全花了将近一个月的时间
circumnavigating Australia in a new and never before
以前所未有的新方式环游澳大利亚
seen show of force that has left the Australians
澳大利亚人看到了武力的展示
feeling particularly vulnerable ever since
从此感到特别脆弱
the PLA N's trip around Australia came at a
解放军在澳大利亚的旅行是在
rather unique time in Australia's history
澳大利亚历史上相当独特的时期
when the country's own navy has
当国家自己的海军
been languishing away for years
已经憔悴多年
and as Australia's traditional alliance with the
作为澳大利亚与
United States is coming under increasing strain with
美国正面临越来越大的压力
Donald Trump back in the White House again
唐纳德·特朗普再次回到白宫
Australia's modern navy is currently in a
澳大利亚的现代海军目前正处于
dismal state and it's the smallest and most
惨淡的状态，它是最小和最多的
outdated it's been since the Second World War
从二战开始就过时了
the PLAN frigate and cruiser that circumnavigated
那艘巡洋舰和巡洋舰
the Australian continent carried with them a combined
澳大利亚大陆携带着
total of 144 vertical launch missile cells
总共144个垂直发射导弹单元
interestingly
有趣的是
pretty close to the entire Australia
相当接近整个澳大利亚
Navy's 10 warships combined total of just
海军的10艘战舰加起来
200 vertical launch missile cells
200个垂直发射导弹单元
it was also the furthest south that
这也是最南端
the PLAN has so far ever sailed
到目前为止，计划已经启航
and the message it sent to
以及它发送到的消息
Australia was crystal clear
澳大利亚清澈见底
even though Beijing said that the warships were
尽管北京说军舰是
constantly operating within international
不断在国际范围内运作
waters and they had every legal right to do so
水域，他们完全有合法权利这样做
as every other navy does all the time
就像其他海军一直做的那样
the message that the Australian homeland was vulnerable
澳大利亚本土易受攻击的信息
to Chinese military action in the event of Australia
中国在澳大利亚的军事行动
or US military bases in Australia intervening to defend
或者美国在澳大利亚的军事基地介入保卫
Taiwan during an invasion scenario was clear as day
台湾在入侵场景中一清二楚
and it came as China's navy has continued
与此同时，中国海军继续
expanding its reach in other areas as well
扩大其在其他领域的影响力
the same month as the PLAN flotilla was
与PLAN舰队同月
busy circumnavigating Australia
忙于环游澳大利亚
the Japanese defense minister stated that plan
日本防卫大臣表示，该计划
warships had passed through the waters around the
战舰已经通过了周围的水域
country's southern Reiuq Islands between the Japanese
日本南部的Reiuq群岛
mainland and Taiwan a total of 68 times throughout
大陆和台湾共有68次
2024 a massive increase in frequency from the only 21
2024年，频率从仅有的21个大幅增加
reported times that they did so back in 2021
报告了他们在2021年这样做的次数
a few months later in June of 2025
几个月后2025年6月
the same Japanese defense minister said that
同一位日本防卫大臣说
one of the PLA N's aircraft carriers
PLA N的航空母舰之一
the Liao Ning
辽宁号
was found down in waters to the
在水下被发现
east of the island of Iwo Jima
硫磺岛以东
marking the first known time that a
标记第一个已知时间
Chinese aircraft carrier has ever sailed
中国航母曾经航行过
beyond the so called second island chain
超越所谓的第二岛链
the rear line of defense the US employs
美国使用的后防线
against China that is centered on Guam
针对以关岛为中心的中国
and perhaps most notably of all
也许最值得注意的是
there's the enormous construction project that
有一个巨大的建设项目
satellites have recently captured going on just to
卫星最近捕捉到
the southwest of China's capital city Beijing
中国首都北京的西南部
taking a closer look at the site
仔细看看网站
this was what it looked like when taken by
这是它被拿走时的样子
satellite imagery on February 5th, 2022
2022年2月5日的卫星图像
just a little over three years ago
就在三年多前
before this video's production
在这段视频制作之前
it doesn't really look like very
它看起来不是很像
much of notice happening yet
很多通知还在发生
but then simply fast forward the clock
然后简单地将时钟快进
by a year to February 25th of 2023
到2023年2月25日
and you'll see that the entire area has been
你会看到整个地区已经
completely cleared out of everything that used to exist
彻底清除了曾经存在的一切
there  with all of the previously existing
那里有所有以前存在的
residential buildings flattened and erased
住宅楼被夷为平地
then fast forward the clock by a little over
然后将时钟快进一点
another year to 20 sixth of june of 2024
再过一年到2024年6月20日
and you'll see another huge change with
你会看到另一个巨大的变化
a massive new monumental construction
一个巨大的新纪念碑建筑
project taking shape in the area
该地区正在形成的项目
with the whole place now looking basically
现在整个地方看起来基本上
nothing like it used to back in early 2022
与2022年初的情况完全不同
fast forward just about another
快进到另一个
year later to March of 2025
一年后到2025年3月
and you'll notice a complex of
你会注意到一种复杂的
buildings taking shape in the center
建筑物正在中心成形
and with dozens of construction cranes still active
几十台建筑起重机仍在工作
making this appear to be a truly
让这看起来像是一个真正的
enormous construction effort
巨大的建设工作量
Chinese government websites have not publicly
中国政府网站尚未公开
commented on any of this construction to date
对迄今为止的任何结构发表评论
and the Chinese government has refused to
中国政府拒绝
answer any questions pertaining to the
回答与
construction site by journalists
建筑工地记者
that has left a lot of speculation
这留下了很多猜测
online as to what exactly this huge
网上到底有什么巨大的
construction project going on actually is
正在进行的建设项目实际上是
and to most outsiders it certainly
对大多数局外人来说，这当然是
appears to be something military related
似乎与军事有关
the final image of the construction site taken
拍摄的建筑工地最终图像
in March of 2025 appears to show around 100
2025年3月似乎显示大约100
construction cranes active at the site that are
现场活跃的建筑起重机
busy building deep subterranean tunnels
忙着建造深层地下隧道
facilities and passageways that all seem to be
设施和通道似乎都
being reinforced by thick layers of concrete
被厚厚的混凝土层加固
making whatever is going on here appearing to be
让这里发生的一切看起来像是
an extremely sensitive military PLA site
一个极其敏感的解放军军事基地
the area is truly huge
面积真的很大
coming in at around 15 acres or
大约15英亩或
five square kilometers in total
总共五平方公里
or in other words roughly 10 times the
或者换句话说大约是
size of the Pentagon near Washington DC
华盛顿特区附近五角大楼的规模
the building that is usually regarded as the
通常被视为
world's largest office building currently
目前世界上最大的办公楼
some high ranking US defense officials have voiced
一些美国高级国防官员表示
their belief that the site is being constructed to
他们认为该网站的建设是为了
offer greater security for high level Chinese officials
为中国高级官员提供更大的安全保障
from advanced US bunker buster munitions during a time
来自美国先进的掩体炸弹
of war
战争
or even from US nuclear weapons
甚至是美国的核武器
as evidenced by all of the extensive and deep
正如所有广泛而深刻的
subterranean construction going on at the site
现场正在进行地下施工
and all of the secrecy surrounding it
以及围绕它的所有秘密
it's probable that with the site
很可能有了网站
being built so close by to Beijing
建在离北京这么近的地方
this new complex captured in satellite imagery
卫星图像捕捉到了这个新建筑群
could become the PLA's new top military
可能会成为解放军新的顶级军队
headquarters and serve as China's wartime command
并担任中国战时指挥部
center during an invasion of Taiwan scenario
入侵台湾场景中的中心
serving a highly similar role as the
扮演与
Pentagon does for the United States military
五角大楼为美国军方所做的
but on a vastly larger physical scale
但在更大的物理规模上
as often concerns the People's
就像人们经常关心的那样
Republic of China however
中华民国然而
matters of such importance as massive
重大事件
subterranean military fortresses
地下军事堡垒
barges designed for huge armored amphibious invasions
为大型装甲两栖入侵而设计的驳船
and remote airfields designed for target
和为目标设计的偏远机场
practicing of US warships in the Taiwanese
美国军舰在台湾的演习
capital are rarely ever mentioned or discussed
资本很少被提及或讨论
publicly by the country's government
由该国政府公开
while China spent the past several decades
虽然中国在过去的几十年里
gradually opening itself up to the world
逐渐向世界开放
China has also continued growing even more
中国也在继续增长
authoritarian and centralized around the
专制和集中
leadership and vision of Xi Jinping
习近平的领导力和远见
China is currently ranked as the third least free
中国目前排名第三
country in the world in terms of freedom of the press
世界上新闻自由的国家
just barely behind the blatantly
只是勉强落后于公然
totalitarian states of North Korea and Eritrea
朝鲜和厄立特里亚的极权国家
there are still many elements about
还有很多关于
China that remain closely guarded and
中国仍然严密戒备
highly sensitive subjects of the state
高度敏感的国家话题
and perhaps none of them are as controversial
也许它们都没有那么有争议
muddied by propaganda and misunderstood as the
被宣传弄糊涂了，被误解为
events that took place 36 years ago at
发生在36年前的事件
Tiananmen Square in Beijing in June of 1989
1989年6月的北京天安门广场
you're probably already pretty
你可能已经很漂亮了
familiar with this event
熟悉这个事件
and you've probably heard of it by any number of
你可能听说过很多
different names the people with all kinds of
不同的名字各种各样的人
different agendas have attempted to label it as
不同的议程试图将其标记为
the Tiananmen Square Massacre
天安门广场大屠杀
as it is often referred to in the west
就像西方经常提到的那样
the June 4th Incident
六四事变
as it is usually referred to in China
因为它在中国通常被称为
or the more vague Tiananmen
或者更模糊的天安门
Square Incident or uprising
广场事件或起义
many of the images taken from the events that took
许多照片取自
place around Tiananmen Square in 1989 have become some
1989年天安门广场周围的地方已经成为一些
of the most famous photographs ever taken in history
历史上最著名的照片
like the tank man photo that shows a lone never
就像坦克人的照片显示一个孤独的永远不会
identified unknown man standing in front of a column of
身份不明的人站在一列
People's Liberation Army tanks leaving from the square
解放军坦克从广场出发
merely hours after the army had just
就在军队刚刚
violently cleared the square out of tens
暴力清除了广场上的十个人
of thousands of student LED protesters
成千上万的学生LED抗议者
the details of what exactly happened over the 48
48年到底发生了什么的细节
hours before this photograph was taken while the PLA
在这张照片拍摄的几个小时前，解放军
clear Tiananmen Square out is one of the most
清除天安门广场是最
contentious subjects of the entire 21st century
整个21世纪有争议的话题
the official Chinese government story is that only
中国政府的官方说法是
241 people were killed during the army's two day
在军队的两天里，241人被杀
operation to clear out the square of protesters
清除广场抗议者的行动
but multiple outside western sources at
但多个西方以外的消息来源
the time reported much higher figures
时间报告了更高的数字
the U S ambassador to China at the time
当时的美国驻华大使
who was present in Beijing
谁在北京
reported that a minimum of several
报告说至少有几个
hundred people had been killed
一百人被杀
hospital records from Beijing that were compiled
北京的医院记录
shortly afterwards recorded at least 478 deaths
不久之后记录了至少478人死亡
that were likely caused by the events
可能是由事件引起的
Amnesty International initially put the
大赦国际最初把
estimate for the dead at between several
估计死者在几人之间
hundred and close to a thousand
一百个接近一千个
while the Chinese Red Cross initially gave a
而中国红十字会最初给了一个
figure for around 26 deaths during the incident
事件中约有26人死亡
before withdrawing their claim
在撤回索赔之前
under Chinese government pressure
在中国政府的压力下
and the Swiss ambassador to China at the time
和当时的瑞士驻华大使
gave a similar figure of around 27 deaths
给出了大约27人死亡的类似数字
while there are also less credible estimates
虽然也有不太可信的估计
from the British ambassador to China at the
来自英国驻华大使
time who initially gave a dramatically higher
最初给出更高价格的时间
minimum figure of 10,000 deaths
最低死亡人数
but who then later revised his estimate down to
但他后来将他的估计下调至
between 27 and 30 4 hundred deaths instead
27到30之间400人死亡
finding out the true scale of the violence that
找出暴力的真实规模
happened at Tiananmen Square in June of 1989 is
1989年6月发生在天安门广场的是
difficult  if not even outright impossible
即使不是完全不可能，也很困难
because a  China goes to extreme lengths to
因为中国会竭尽全力
enormously censor the event in an attempt to
对事件进行大量审查，试图
bury any memory and discussion about it
埋葬任何关于它的记忆和讨论
and b  western sources were and still are
西方消息来源过去是，现在仍然是
heavily incentivized to embellish or
强烈激励修饰或
overexaggerate the brutality of it
过分夸大它的残忍
searches for Tiananmen Square massacre  June 4th
搜索六四天安门广场大屠杀
Tank man
坦克人
and sensitive numbers like 6 4 for June 4th or 89
和敏感数字，如6月4日的6 4或89
6 4 are all blocked or return no results on
6 4都被屏蔽或返回没有结果
Chinese search engines like Baidu to this day
像百度这样的中国搜索引擎
while posts about the events on Chinese
而关于中国事件的帖子
social media apps like Wechat and Douyin
微信和抖音等社交媒体应用
China's native version of TikTok remain auto
中国本土版本的TikTok仍然是汽车
deleted by algorithms or shadow banned
被算法删除或阴影禁止
the events are entirely omitted from all
事件完全被忽略了
history textbooks in mainland China
中国大陆历史教科书
and even foreign scholars who publish work about
甚至外国学者也发表了关于
the Tiananmen Square events will often be denied
天安门事件经常会被否认
visas or access to the Chinese archives
签证或查阅中国档案
collectively making the Tiananmen Square events
集体制造天安门事件
the most heavily censored event in modern
现代审查最严格的事件
history and probably the most difficult modern
历史和可能是最困难的现代
historical subject to properly research
应适当研究的历史主题
nonetheless
尽管如此
I still made an entire video about my own
我仍然制作了一整段关于我自己的视频
investigation into the Tiananmen Square June 1989
天安门事件调查1989年6月
events in my Modern Conflict series
我的现代冲突系列中的事件
which I create new videos in every single
我在每个单曲中都创建了新视频
month taking deeper dives into more recent
深入到最近的一个月
controversial and darker subject
有争议和黑暗的话题
material surrounding modern wars
现代战争的素材
operations and conflicts
运营与冲突
overi the past four years of doing this
在过去的四年里
I've created around 50 total episodes in
我总共创作了大约50集
modern conflicts covering other topics as
涵盖其他主题的现代冲突
diverse as the undeclared war and skirmishes
不宣而战和小规模冲突
between north and South Korea since 2000
自2000年以来朝鲜和韩国之间
China's policies of oppression against its
中国的压迫政策
Muslim Uighur population in Xinjiang
新疆维吾尔族穆斯林人口
the Myanmar civil war and that regime's modern
缅甸内战和该政权的现代
genocide against its minority Rohingya people
对少数民族罗辛亚人的种族灭绝
the border fights between China
中国边境之争
and India across 2020 and 2021
和印度在2020年和2021年
and dozens of other episodes with brand new ones
还有几十集全新的剧集
like this Tennism Square 1989 episode coming out
就像这一集的Tennist Square 1989
every single month all exclusively on Nebula
每个月都专门在星云上
because of the inherently violent and controversial
因为天生的暴力和争议
details surrounding the discussion of all of this
围绕这一切讨论的细节
my episode investigating what actually
我的插曲调查实际上
took place around Tiananmen Square in June
发生在六月的天安门广场
of 1989 would never work on YouTube
1989年的永远不会在YouTube上工作
because it would instantly become
因为它会立即成为
demonetized and age restricted
废止和年龄限制
which means that YouTube's algorithm
也就是说YouTube的算法
which is based around showing you ads
这是基于向您展示广告
would never be incentivized to actually
永远不会被激励去实际
show the video to you or to promote it
向您展示视频或推广它
I deal with very large numbers in my videos on YouTube
我在YouTube上的视频中处理非常大的数字
getting demonetized and age restricted as they are
被废钞和年龄限制
and that's why I upload all of my episodes in
这就是为什么我上传我所有的剧集
modern conflicts exclusively to Nebula
星云独有的现代冲突
and why signing up to Nebula is the absolute best
以及为什么签约星云绝对是最好的
thing that you can do to support me and my channel
你可以做些什么来支持我和我的频道
and you'll also get access to way more
你还可以获得更多
content than just my own exclusive
内容不仅仅是我自己的独家新闻
Modern Conflict series there as well
现代冲突系列也在那里
because the best part about Nebula is that it's jointly
因为星云最棒的部分是它是联合的
co owned by myself and hundreds of other independent
由我和数百名其他独立人士共同拥有
creators to make the projects that we're all actually
创造者来制作我们都实际参与的项目
deeply excited about without any fear of being censored
对被审查没有任何恐惧感到非常兴奋
or demonetized like we are on YouTube
或者像我们在YouTube上那样去货币化
and that's why there's tons of other new unique content
这就是为什么还有大量其他新的独特内容
on Nebula that's coming out all the time too that you'll
在星云上，它也一直在出来，你会
also love like Neos under exposure series
也喜欢曝光系列下的Neos
Wender Productions the logistics of X Series
Wender Productions X系列的物流
TLDR news is what to follow USA series
TLDR新闻是什么跟随美国系列
and so so many others
还有这么多其他人
I also know that there's a lot of
我也知道有很多
streaming platforms out there right now
现在的流媒体平台
and you don't really want to get stuck with
你不会真的想陷入
another monthly cost to keep track of
另一个每月跟踪的费用
but I also know that if you've watched
但我也知道如果你看过
this all the way through to the end
这一直到最后
there is so much content on
上面有这么多内容
Nebula that you'll love as well
你也会喜欢的星云
and so much more coming out with every new month
每个月都会有更多的产品问世
that you could consider a lifetime
你可以考虑一辈子
membership to Nebula as well
也是星云的会员
you just pay once
你只需支付一次
and then you'll get lifetime access to everything
然后你就可以终生接触到一切
that I and hundreds of other creators will ever
我和数百名其他创作者将永远
produce on Nebula for as long as we both last
在星云上生产只要我们还活着
and then you'll never have to worry about a
然后你就再也不用担心
recurring subscription or ads ever again
再次重复订阅或广告
that's the best way possible to support
这是最好的支持方式
what I'm doing here on real life lore
我在现实生活中做的事情
but even if you'd rather not make that
但即使你不想这么做
large of an upfront commitment
大量前期承诺
you can still greatly help support me by signing up
你仍然可以通过注册来极大地帮助支持我
for a yearly or a monthly subscription to Nebula as
每年或每月订阅星云
well
井
which you can get for a fantastic deal with 40% off
你可以以40%的折扣获得一笔很棒的交易。
by scanning the QR code or clicking the button
通过扫描二维码或点击按钮
here on your screen right now or by following the
现在在您的屏幕上或通过以下方式
link that's down below in the description
下面描述中的链接
any of which will also get you access to
其中任何一个也可以让您访问
everything that's on Nebula for the very low
星云上的一切都非常低
price of just $3 a month or $36 a year
价格只有3美元一个月或36美元一年
I hope that you'll consider signing up and as
我希望你能考虑报名参加
always thank you so much for watching
总是非常感谢你的收看